本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译   米小勒   S很爱笑   CS小明漫画家    我叫魏碧慧   小奶
翻译   蔡茸茸   Marshal同学   天启章鱼X    lottie筱妤   小欠
时间轴   太太乐叽叽    安妮       后期   小亲斤
校对   米小勒       总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
第一季 第八集
北极光阵地
[国安局最后一个尚在运作的指令中心]
嘿  嘿  嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
世界之巅又一个静谧的周六之夜
Another quiet Saturday night here at the top of the world.
如果你还听得到我的声音  那我只能说
If you can hear my voice, let me just say
恭喜你还活着
I'm glad you're still alive.
僵尸爆发第三年来的大规模僵尸狂潮
The Great Zombie Zunami of 03
正持续将广袤的草原吞噬
continues to pound the prairie into dust,
并且从内布拉斯加州向南入侵堪萨斯
headed south from Nebraska into Kansas.
这一超越百万人数的僵尸大军
This hive minded crowd of a million plus zombies
所到之处毫无规律且破坏力惊人  所以
is crushing everything in its random path, so
眼睛都擦亮点
watch your ass out there.
老老实实待在家里
Keep your hands and feet inside the boat,
别出去招惹怪兽们哦
and don't feed the animals.
这里是市民Z
This is Citizen Z.
今日到此结束
Signing off.
[一氧化碳浓度值]
梅兹
Mays!
有种比比啊  梅兹  出来跟哥较量较量
What you got, Mays? What you got?
埃尔南德斯
Hernandez!
你能声音轻点不
Could you do that more quietly?
矮油
Hello there.
有人想非法入侵哥的系统吗
Is someone trying to hack me ?
想从侧门偷溜进来是不
Sneaking in the side door, huh?
没人可以黑得了哥
Nobody hacks me.
永远别想
Not now. Not ever.
没哥的邀请休想进来
No entry without an invitation.
靠  哥正在努力了好吗
Jeez, I'm working here!
现在让哥跟在你背后  慢慢地...
Now to follow you right back...
你个愚蠢的菜鸟
You clumsy dimwitted amateur!
看看我们找到了什么  等等
What do we have here? Wait.
看来是勇敢者的游戏啊
Oh Jumanji.
老兄
Dude!
外太空的火球给基地砸了个大窟窿
A fireball from outer space gives the base a haircut,
你还在这安然无事的呼呼大睡
and you got nothing for me?
星期六之夜要嗨起来了
Saturday night is picking up.
好吧  那看上去还蛮有意思的
Okay, that's pretty crazy town.
那不可能啊
That's impossible.
[没有探测到任何生命形式]
[内布拉斯州某处]
哥曾经看到过报道说  一个人是可以喝自己尿液的
I read once that you could drink your own urine.
但哥尿的不是尿  是寂寞
But all I'm pissin' is dust.
在那坐以待毙  水是不会自己找上门的
Water isn't gonna find you just sitting there.
为什么你还能这么活力充沛
Why are you so freaking chipper?
我也百思不得其解呢
I've been wondering that myself.
也许我保存住了我娇贵的体液没流失呢
Maybe it's cuz I conserve my precious bodily fluids.
那是什么声音
What is that?
是地震的声音吗
Is it an earthquake?
更像是僵尸震的声音
More like a zombie quake.
这些天杀的就是没完没了
Goddamn guys just won't quit.
我建议咱还是赶紧逃吧
I suggest we run for it.
赶快啊各位  打起精神来嘛
Come on, people. Pick it up.
我...
I...
我们
We...
做不到  严重脱水了
Can't. Dehydrated.
快起来  继续前进
Come on. Keep movin'.
动起来
Come on.
大家走吧
Let's go.
快点  动起来
Come on! Move it!
菲比斯医生家
停尸间
县验尸官
往这边来
This way!
等等
Wait!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
不许动  否则我开枪了
Don't move or I'll shoot!
来吧
Go ahead.
来宣布我的末日吧
Make my apocalypse.
让我直达天际
Reach for the sky!
好吧
All right, ummm.
把你的手  举起来
Put your hands... up.
举起手来
Hands up.
没错  就那样
Yeah, yeah, like that.
很好
Yeah.
我是友非敌
I am friend.
朋友
Friend?
你可以摘下头盔
You can take your helmet off.
空气很安全
The air is safe.
空气不安全
The air is not safe.
不  空气是安全的
Yes, yes it is. The air is safe.
你看吧
Yeah, see.
空气是安全的
The air is safe.
好的
Okay.
所以  就这样了吗
So that's it?
我们都躺这等死吗
We're all just gonna lie down and die?
多克
Doc!
别闹了  摩菲
Knock it off, Murphy.
三天滴水未进了  老兄
Three days without water, man.
人体遇到瓶颈期了
The human body hits the wall.
外面肯定有成百上千的僵尸
There must be thousands of them.
成千上万
Millions.
他们在迁徙
They're migrating.
迁去哪里
Migrating to where?
去南方过冬
South for the winter.
僵尸们都怕冷
Zs don't like the cold.
这孩子说的没错
Kid's got it.
我们在北达科他州有一块地方
We had a place up in North Dakota
离耶芝堡不远
near Fort Yates,
靠近河边的一小块地方
quiet little place right on the river.
我们几十个人斗胆一试
Couple dozens of us having a go.
虽然僵尸群三不五时地出现
I mean, zombie bison every once in a while,
但那是最糟糕的情况了
but that was as bad as it got.
然后这隆隆声就再也没停过
Then the rumbling started and never stopped.
他们是从哪里来的
Well where'd they come from?
加拿大西部亚伯达省的难民营
Refugee camp up in Alberta.
那里人数过百万  缺水短食
Over a million people. No food. No water.
情况非常糟糕
It got ugly.
一周之内  所有的人都变异了
They all turned in a week.
我们应该继续前进
We shoulda kept running.
你们绕不过去吗
You couldn't get around them?
这一大群有好几英里宽  而且它们都有意识
This herd is miles wide. I mean it's got a mind of its own.
你没法快到能绕开它们
You can't move fast enough to get around it.
而且独行的僵尸到处都是  会加入群体
And every single thing it overruns just adds to its crowd,
有速度很快的僵尸  健康的僵尸
you know fast zombies, healthy zombies,
就像刚刚扑倒我朋友巴克的那只
like the ones that just got my friend Buck.
伙计  跟我们分着喝吧
Hey man, you gonna share that with the class?
这不是水
It ain't water.
传着喝吧  不管它是什么
Pass it around, whatever it is.
慢点喝
Go easy on it.
私家酿的  不是每个人都能接受的
Homemade hooch ain't for everyone.
慢点  拜托  给我留点
Easy man. Come on. It's got to last me.
这是防冻液和...
Anti-freeze and...
蓖麻油
Castor oil.
我们得离开这
We've got to get out of here.
没错
He's right.
好吧  这房间不安全
Okay, this room isn't secure.
我们得找个更安全的地方
We got to find some place more secure.
后面是什么地方
What's back there?
停尸房
Morgue.
来吧
Let's go.
你听到她说了  来啊
You heard the lady! Let's go!
好  好  就来
Yeah, yeah, all right.
没路了
Nuh-uh, no way.
这里是死胡同
This place is a death trap.
好  很好  这茶是
Good, very good. This tea is...
伯爵茶吗
Earl Grey?
没错  伯爵茶
That's right. Earl Grey.
我最喜欢的茶
It's my favorite.
也是我最喜欢的
Huh. It's my favorite too.
我们有很多共同点
We have in common much, you and I.
尤里
So, Yuri.
我觉得我们得追溯一下
I think we got to address
这头八百磅重的大猩猩的由来
the eight hundred pound gorilla in the room.
不  那是一种比喻
No. It's an expression.
是美国的俚语
It's American slang.
我不懂
Sorry.
好吧  这么说吧
All right. Look,
你是怎么落到这来的
okay, how did you get here?
好的  好的  好的
Yes, yes, yes.
从ISS来的
Ummm, on I.S.S..
宇宙空间站
International Space Station.
你一直在宇宙空间站里
You were on the International Space Station?
可不是吗  空间站还在运行
Oh that's right, it's still up there.
当休斯顿和莫斯科...
When Houston and Moscow...
停止  废掉的时候  我们被孤立了
stop, went dark, we were... alone.
那已经是三年前的事情了
Wow, that was like three years ago.
你自己待了那么长时间
That's a long time to be alone.
很长时间  没错
A long time, yes.
之后  食物吃光了
After time, the food was gone.
系统停止运行了
The system...stop, stop working.
没有氧气  也不能取暖了
The air, the heat.
所以联盟号逃生舱把我带到你这
So Soyuz escape pod bring me to you.
那定是一段地狱般的旅程
Wow, that must've been one hell of a ride.
那其他人呢
What about the others?
你指的是
Others?
你们剩下的工作人员呢
The rest of your crew?
死了
No crew.
只剩尤里
Only Yuri.
你们队员呢
Your crew?
不在了
No crew.
只剩市民Z了
Only Citizen Z.
为了生存
To surviving.
为了生存干杯
可怜的狗狗
Poor dog.
它一定是玩得太累了
All the excitement must've tuckered him out.
我在想他们要去哪
I wonder where they're all going.
无处可去
Nowhere.
他们是僵尸
They're zombies.
好在他们没有领头的
Be glad they don't have a leader.
现在怎么办
Now what?
我们等他们散去
We wait them out.
我们不能在这坐以待毙
We can't just stay here and wait to die.
你们听到了吗  还是我幻听了
Do you hear that or is that just in my head?
我希望是老鼠
I hope it's rats.
我想声音是从这里传出来的
I think it's coming from in here.
哎呦  我去
Awww, damn.
发生这种事还让人怎么休息
How's a guy supposed to relax with all that going on?
我来开
I'll open it.
你动手
You pike it.
别开抽屉  别管它不就行了
Don't open that drawer. Just leave it alone.
淡定
Calm down.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
我觉得在这里面
I think it's coming from this one.
你还好吗
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
摩菲  劳驾下次帮帮忙
Feel free to help out next time, Murphy.
你头发里有只耳朵
You got an ear in your hair.
又怎么了
What's new?
他们要闯进来了
They're coming in.
冷静
Settle down.
这样好吗
I don't know.
我们别无选择
We don't have much choice.
我才不要进那玩意里
No way in hell am I getting in that thing.
一定很有意思
Well, this is gonna be fun.
好了  够了  朋友我不要了
Okay. Good... No more, my friend.
我的朋友
My friend.
好的
Okay.
我将要向你展示的东西
What I'm about to show you,
没有人见过
no other human being has seen.
只有朋友可见  这是朋友圈共享的
This is for friends only. This is a friend zone.
当这一切发生后  所有人都...
So after what happened, you know after everybody...
我开始了工作
I started working.
收集数据  整理资料  运行程序
Collecting data, collating, running algorithms,
我用尽各种手段
doing anything that I could do to
将所有线索拼凑起来
put the pieces of the puzzle together.
世界各地能都通信吗
There is global communication?
是啊  我是说一部分可以
Yeah, I mean some.
外面还是有幸存者的
There are survivors out there.
你是  一个人运转这些设备吗
And you... alone keep this in operation?
是啊  这只有我一个人
Uh, yeah. I mean I'm the only person here.
网络  卫星  城里的摄像头都由你操控吗
Internet, satellites, the cameras in cities?
是啊  是啊
Yes. Yes.
保姆监视器  安全摄像头  网络摄像头
Nanny cams, security cams, web cams.
只要是能发送信号的装置
Anything that puts out a signal
或者任何能连上网络的东西
or is somehow connected to the grid
我都能轻松掌控
I can reach out and touch it.
我就是国安局  亲
I'm the NSA, baby.
多沉重的负担啊
What a terrible burden.
什么
What?
目睹这么多惨状
To see so much pain.
单凭一个人怎么承受得了
One man cannot carry this alone.
抱歉  朋友
I'm sorry, friend.
别这样
Just stop that.
好了  咱们继续
All right, back to the tour.
然后这里  这里的
And for here, the...
供电  温度  空气供应  你...
the power, the heat, the fresh air, you...
都是你控制的吗
you control all these things?
没错  咱们俩好着呢
Oh yeah, you and I are gonna be fine.
我这有太阳能  发电机
I got solar power, generators,
饮用水过滤器  空气过滤器
water filters, air filters.
还有够吃上几十年的食物
Enough food to last for a couple of decades.
还有足够的酒
And enough booze to last for
大概也能撑个几年
I dunno a couple fun years.
我知道你们那的人有多爱伏特加
I know how much you people love your Vodka.
哈士奇狗
Husky dog.
狗不是都喜欢到处撒欢吗
Dog usually run and play, yes?
你的狗  它...
Your dog, he...
它啥都不干  你怎么看
he do nothing. Why do you think?
你的问题还真多啊  好同志
You sure do ask a lot of questions, comrade.
尤里
Yuri,
尤里  听我说
Yuri, listen to me.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我认为
I think
我们能找到僵尸大灾变的原因
that we can find out the reason for the zombie apocalypse.
答案肯定就在这的某个地方
The answer is here somewhere.
不过我们得当心了
But we got to be careful.
有人想黑进我的系统
Somebody tried to hack into my system.
还有别的这样子的基地吗
There are other bases like this?
我不知道  我猜可能有吧
I don't know. I guess.
外面有人想知道我到底知道些什么
Someone out there wants to know what I know.
我们谁都不能相信
And we can't trust anybody.
我不想死在这
I don't want to die in here.
反正你出去也活不成
Well you ain't gonna live out here.
我知道
I know.
你先上  孩子  你们是祖国的未来
After you, kid. Age before beauty.
准备好
Okay.
好的
All right.
你俩谁下一个
One of you goes next.
咱俩剪刀石头布呗
Rock, paper, scissors?
大爷  您九岁吗
What are you nine?
不玩算鸟  哥先进
Fine, I'll take it.
你最好搞快点
You better hurry up.
这个给你  多克
Here you go, Doc.
好了
Okay.
你先来  下一个是我
All right, I'll take the next one.
我害怕呆在密闭空间里
I'm no good in tight spaces.
赶紧进去
Get in.
臣妾觉得臣妾做不到啊
I don't think I can do this.
沃伦  你最好搞快点
Warren, you better hurry.
知道
I am.
该死  现在怎么办
Oh damn. Now what?
来吧
Come on.
好吧  好吧
Okay. Okay.
这里主要用作仓库
It's storage mostly,
储藏备用电源  当然还能用来练高尔夫
backup power, and of course the driving range.
这儿这么多机械  打这么硬的球合适吗
Is good idea to hit hard ball off machinery?
有时候的确需要修理打坏了的机器  不过
Well from time to time we do require repairs, but
我还能怎么办呢
what can I do?
又不能出去打球  球都会不见的
Can't play outside. I'd lose all my balls.
给我球杆
Driver.
因为外面有雪
Because of the snow.
球是白色的  雪也是白色的
You know the balls are white and the snow is white.
我会帮你提高幽默感的
We'll work on your humor.
啊  耶
Ahhh, yeah.
-意思是还不错吗  -呜
- Means is good? - Oooooh.
那意思是很不错  递根球杆来
That means it's great. Hand me an iron.
啊  真棒
Ahhh, yes.
耶  好家伙
Yeah, baby!
你笑什么
Why do you laugh?
你那一球太糟了
That was terrible.
别闹了
Stop.
别抽着哟
Don't choke.
狗屎
Shit!
怎么回事  你喜欢那个  左转左转
What's up? You like that? Go left! Go left!
我完全不喜欢这个
I totally do not like this.
把他们往那边引  把他们往那边引
Lure them this way, lure them this way.
我不喜欢  我不喜欢
I don't like! I don't like!
我不喜欢啦  逮住那个
I don't like! Grab that one!
看见了吗
You see this?
-看到了  好棒  -我杀僵尸了  我杀僵尸了
- Yes! Yes! - I'm killing. I'm killing.
帮我记作六杆吧
Put me down for a six,
四杆
four,
三杆吧
three.
嗯  算三杆吧  这是个小鸟球
Uh, three! It's a birdie!
嗨  同志
Yo comrade?!
尤里?
Yuri?
尤里  你在干嘛
Yuri, what are you doing?
这个我们空间站里有
This we had on space station.
行了  走吧  别把东西弄坏了
Okay, well come on before you break something.
我还以为这个球找不回来了呢
I thought I lost this ball.
你必须打完这一洞  现在是加时赛了
You got to finish this hole. It's a playoff.
骤死赛[一球定胜负]
Sudden death.
骤死听起来可不好玩哦  西蒙
Sudden death does not sound like fun game, Simon.
抱歉  你说什么
Sorry, what?
决出胜负来就不好玩了嘛
No fun your game of death.
你就是个怪咖  西蒙
You are odd duck, Simon.
西蒙
Simon?
-不准离开我们  -你待着别动就行了
- Don't you leave us. - Shhh. Just stay real still.
-摩菲  你要敢跑...  -别动了
-Murphy. Don't you leave. - Don't move.
我必须要把你送到加利福尼亚
I got to get you to California.
你已经尽到你最大努力了
You got me as far as you could.
摩菲  求你了
Murphy, please.
他们是怎么死的
What's made them dead?
怎样才能杀死他们
How do we kill them?
你必须冲着头部开枪
You got to shoot for the head.
真的吗  直接爆头
This is true? Shoot the head?
是的  爆头  只有这样才能阻止它们
Yeah, kill the brain. It's the only way to stop them.
再高点瞄准
Aim higher.
去死吧  僵尸
Die zombie!
我们比他们强大
We're stronger than they.
我们是指人类吗
Us humans?
是的  想杀死我们可没这么简单
Mmm-hmmm, yes. It's not so simple to kill us.
想杀死我们手段可要多点
There is not one way but instead many ways to die.
来点爆米花怎么样  你想吃爆米花吗
How 'bout some popcorn? Do you want some popcorn?
我去拿点爆米花
I'm gonna go make us some popcorn.
死吧  僵尸  去死吧
Die zombie! Die!
掌握秘诀之后是不是杀得更容易些
Is easy to kill when you know the secret.
我要去趟厕所[朝着头部打]
I'm gonna hit the head.
是的  直接爆头
Yep, shoot in head.
不不不  我是指
No, no, no, I mean...
算了  我马上回来
Nevermind. I'll be right back.
再去拿点伏特加和零食
Oh, bring vodka with snack.
好的  好的  我马上回来
Oh yeah, sure. Yeah, sure. I'll be back.
死吧  僵尸  死死死死  去死吧
Die zombie! Die, die, die, die, die!
国际空间站氧气已耗尽
国际空间站烧毁于近地轨道
据推测站内所有人员均已死亡
死叛徒想耍我
Judas monkey sauce.
你是掉坑里了吗
Did you fall in?
什么
What?
稍等一下  我马上完事了
Just a second. I'm almost done.
掉坑里  就是指整个人都掉进马桶里了
Fall in. Like you fall in toilet, your whole self.
真好笑  是吧
It's good joke, yes?
是的  是的  我听懂了
Yes, yes, I get that.
用词还挺形象啊
Your slang's coming right along.
我马上就出去了  等一会
I'll be right out. Wait one second.
离那个仪表盘远点  尤里
Step away from that panel, Yuri.
你对国际空间站里伙伴们用的那点手段
You're not gonna do me like you did your
可对付不了我
comrades on the International Space Station.
西蒙
Simon.
市民Z  我的名字是市民Z
Citizen Z. My name is Citizen Z.
没有人叫我西蒙
No one calls me Simon.
甚至没人知道我叫西蒙
No one even knows my name is Simon.
你是怎么知道的
So how do you know?
因为我们是朋友
Because we are friends.
好朋友
Close friends.
朋友  我们不是朋友
Friends. We're not friends.
你欺骗我
You lied to me.
你告诉我你到底是谁
Now you tell me who you really are.
你问错问题了
You ask the wrong question.
离控制板远一点
Back away from that panel.
退后
Back away!
为什么要穿航空服
And what's with the suit, huh?
这个问题好多了
That is better question.
你是想  你是想冻住我吗
Are you gonna... you gonna try and freeze me out?
放开我
Get off me!
给我老实点别动
Don't even blink
不然我就把你脑袋崩回俄罗斯摩尔曼斯克
or I'll blow your brains back to Murmansk.
干什么
What?
你们又不想咬我  你们想干什么
You don't want to eat me, what do you want?
好吧  我就是这个瞎子国的独眼国王
Great. I'm the one-eyed king in the land of the blind.
你为什么来这里
Why are you really here?
谁派你来的  那些黑客吗
Who sent you? The hackers?
狗狗怎么了
What is wrong with dog?
你不准问问题
You don't ask questions!
现在是我在审你
I'm interrogating you!
狗在睡觉  不是吗
Dog is sleepy, no?
你来之前他都好好的
He was fine before you got here.
你对他做了什么
What did you do to him?
你给他下毒了吗
Did you poison him?
问你自己
Ask yourself.
狗怎么了
What is wrong with dog?
天呐  你给我的狗下毒了
God, you poisoned my dog?
如果你做了任何伤害他的事
If you did anything to hurt him...
你个狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
那不是爸爸
That's not daddy.
谢谢  是的  我们准备点餐了
Thank you. Yes, we are ready to order.
我快饿死了
Oh I'm so hungry.
我很想吃帝王蟹
I would love to have some Alaskan King Crab.
还很想吃炒饭
And I would love to have the rice pilaf.
那就太好了  我能再...
That will be so nice. And could I please...
我不想孤单地死去
I don't wanna die alone.
好吧其实我们的死都是孤单的
Well, I mean we all die alone, really.
我不想死在这
I don't wanna die in here.
我现在还不想死
I don't wanna die now.
我不想死
I don't wanna die.
雏鸟乐队
The Yardbirds.
主音吉他手是埃里克·克拉普顿和吉米·佩奇
Eric Clapton and Jimmy Page. Yep.
不  先是杰夫·贝克然后才是吉米·佩奇
No, Jeff Beck then Jimmy Page.
滚出去  滚开
Get out of here! Go away!
深呼吸  伙计  深呼吸
Try to breathe, man. Just breathe.
这里没有氧气了
There's no air in here.
我得逃离这黑暗  我坚持不了了
I got to get out of the darkness. I can't take it.
如果我们一起出去  就可以打败他们
If we all go at once, we can overpower them.
不  不  伙计  谁都不能出去
No. No, man. No one's going.
冷静  伙计  冷静
Chill, man. Chill.
一
One.
二
Two.
奥蒂斯  你冷静些
Otis, be cool man. Be cool.
三
Three.
奇想乐队
The Kinks.
瑞·戴维斯  戴夫·戴维斯[乐队成员]
Ray Davies. Dave Davies.
你是不是给我的狗下毒了
Did you poison my dog?!
如果他死了
If he dies,
-我会要了你的命  -你不会杀我的
- I will kill you. - You won't kill me!
西蒙
Simon,
你杀不死我
you can't.
西蒙  你要留心听我说
Simon, you need to listen.
你怎么知道我叫什么
How do you know my name?
怎么知道你叫什么  我是你的朋友
How do I know your name? I am friend.
非常亲密的朋友
Close friend.
你不认识我  但我认识你
You don't know me, but I know you.
你对我的狗下了什么毒  快说
You tell me what you used to poison my dog! Answer me!
问你自己  狗到底怎么了
Ask yourself, what is wrong with dog?!
我不知道
I don't know!
你知道的
You know answer!
西蒙  这很重要
Simon. Is important. Hmmm?
西蒙  你知道什么
Simon. What do you know?
让我们来找找答案  西蒙  好好想想
We need to find out what you know. Simon, think.
你都知道什么
What do you know?
今天有什么不同
What's different about today?
一个脑抽的俄国宇航员
Some crazy cosmonaut broke into my secure
闯进我严密防守且偏远的情报中心
and isolated listening post
对我和我的狗下了毒
and poisoned me and my dog.
我不相信你就这点儿能耐  西蒙
You have to do better than that, Simon.
好好回答我的问题
Try to answer the question.
狗到底怎么了
What is wrong with dog?
你去死吧
Go to hell.
今天有什么不同
What's different about today?
狗到底怎么了
What is wrong with dog?
你知道什么
What do you know?
你就这点儿出息吗
Is this all your fight?
拿出点儿能耐来  西蒙
You have to do better, Simon.
为了你的生命而反抗
You must fight for life.
西蒙  反抗  战斗
Simon, fight! Fight!
为生命而战
Fight for life!
拜托  帮帮我们
Help us, please.
你是人类吗
What are you?
给我的女儿留点水吧
Leave some water for my girl.
要是你看见一个穿红夹克的男人...
If you see a man, red jacket...
至少帮我告诉他  我们娘俩还活着
Tell him we're still alive. At least do that.
今天有什么不同
What's different today?
狗到底怎么了
What is wrong with dog?
你知道什么
What do you know?
我...不能...呼吸
I...can't...breathe...
很好  为什么
Good.Why?
什么
What?
-我快窒息了  -对  为什么
- You're... suffocating me. - Yes. Why?
你...扼着我的喉咙
You're... strangling me.
再具体些
More specific.
什么
What?
你喘不过气是因为...
You can't breathe because...
没有  氧  气
There is... no... oxygen.
加油  小子  呼吸吧
Come on, boy. Come on now.
太好了
There you go.
好
All right.
该走了
It's time to go.
他们都走了吗
They've gone?
是
Yeah.
你真的回来了
You came back?
对
I did.
你从哪弄的
Where'd you get that?
有一家人没挺住  从他们那拿来的
Took it... from a dead family.
太谢谢了
Thank you.
爽
Oooh, yeah.
看来又只剩咱俩了  小狗
Looks like it's just me and you again, pup.
摩菲  你怎么做到的
Murphy, how did you do this?
别说了  我都不想知道了
No, I don't even want to know.
一万说你的那些话我收回
I take back everything 10K said about you.
我还以为沃伦已经死在他们手里了
Well, you know I thought they got Warren already.
不是说你不行  但你差点就死了
No offense, but you were almost dead.
但是摩菲老兄  你太强了吧
But Murphy, man you are unreal.
他们都去哪了  你得杀了多少啊
Where'd they all go? How many did you kill?
我们出门不会看见路两边都堆着
Are we gonna go outside and see them piled like
一丈高的死人吧
ten-deep on the sidewalk?
低调  低调  这就对了
Down low. Down low. Down low. There you go.
怎么了
What?
我这么长时间
That is the most words
头回听你一口气说这么多话  小子
I ever heard come out of your sound hole, kid.
我过去可喜欢吃这个了
These used to be my favorite food.
你从哪找到的金鱼饼干
Where the hell did you find goldfish?
我有独特的找饼干技巧
I'm a goldfish magnet.
不过我确实不知道你喜欢吃这个
I didn't know they were your favorite though.
请来一份多汁的肋眼牛排外加一大包烤土豆片
I like a juicy rib eye with a loaded baked potato.
你个食品雷达能给我扫描扫描吗
Can your psycho food radar find that?
你就是一贪得无厌的老混蛋  多克
Yeah Doc, you're one greedy bastard.
你知道吗
You know that?
敬摩菲
To Murphy.
也许护送你是任务
You may be the mission.
但今天  你是我们真正的朋友
But today you became our friend.
谢谢你
Thank you.
同意
Here, here.
干杯
Cheers.
别这么客气
Okay, okay, okay.
我这么做纯粹是受不了多克抱怨个没完
I only did it to stop Doc's constant whining.
说得有理
That is totally fair.
这是牛肉干吗
Is this beef jerky?
你别整袋都吃了啊
You're not taking the whole bag, are you?
那么  可以出发了吗
So ummm, can we go now?
我想上路了  所以大家都动身吧
I need to go. So I need you to go.
我想走了
I need to go.